翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
Hello everybody in this video we're
观众姥爷好！（*＾-＾*）这个视频
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
taking a slightly different approach to
将采用一种稍微不同的方式来介绍
interesting facts about Windows
关于Windows的有趣事实
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
This is the first time in a couple of years I'm
这是几年来我第一次向你展示
showing you cool things about Windows. So
关于Windows的酷炫内容
I wanted it to be special
所以我希望这次能够特别一些
So this is the first time I'm
这是我第一次
narrating this kind of video
为这种视频做旁白
and I've also permanently switched editing software
而且我也永久更换了编辑软件
I'm now using the DaVinci Resolve
我现在正在使用达芬奇（视频剪辑软件）
Pretty unusual experience from me
对我来说是一次非同寻常的经历
and I'm still a beginner so any
而且我还是个初学者
feedback in the comments down below would be welcome
所以欢迎在下面的评论中提供任何反馈
But anyway let's begin!
不说这么多了，进入正题吧！
Welcome to 11 interesting facts about Windows 11
欢迎了解关于Windows 11的11个有趣事实
starting with number 11 the black screen of death
从第11个开始，黑屏死机
We're going to countown just like in the previous episodes
我们将像之前的几集一样倒着数
In the past we've seen the green screen of death
过去我们看到了绿屏死机
the color choice for The Insider builds
这是内部版本选择的
the rare undocumented red screen of death which
还有罕见未记录的红屏死机
was likely actually a blue hu shifted due to graphical issues
实际上可能是由于图形问题导致的蓝屏色调偏移
but the black screen of death was something new and
但黑屏死机在2021年Windows 11泄露时却是全新的意外情况
unexpected with the windows 11 leak way back in 2021
If we quickly hop over to the build
如果我们快速切换到
22000 and kill a system process
版本22000并终止系统进程
We'll see a black screen of death with a blue QR code
我们将看到一个带有蓝色二维码的黑屏死机画面
beautiful
太美
just like most initial Windows 11 cosmetic changes this one was
就像大多数最初的Windows 11外观更改一样，这个更改也是
also incomplete being applied haphazardly
不完整的，被随意应用
Microsoft never commented on such a seemingly fundamental cosmetic change
微软从未对明显的界面变化发表过评论
and a couple builds later
几个版本更新之后
the screen became blue again
蓝屏又回归了
not that anyone cared from what I've seen
就我所言，没人在乎
There wasn't any backlash
没有任何反弹
and it wasn't big news for some reason
而且出于某种原因，这并不是什么大新闻
the community was indifferent
社区对此漠不关心
it might have been a failed experiment it can't be coincidental
这可能是一个失败的实验，第一次构建就出现黑屏死机不可能是巧合
the first build with a black screen of death
also started a revamped log on UI
还启动了以黑色为基色的全新登录界面
with a black root color
The Blue check screen color was likely intended to complement
蓝色检查屏幕可能是为了与关机屏幕的新底色相协调
the new root color of the shutdown screen
and it was pretty thought through
而且它经过了深思熟虑，因为无论是蓝色还是黑色，缩写都没有改变
because the acronym hadn't changed
whether it's blue or black
而且它经过了深思熟虑，因为无论是蓝色还是黑色，缩写都没有改变
it's still a sord
摇摆不定
number 10 you can easily install Windows 11 without  bloatware
第10点，你可以轻松安装没有预装软件的Windows 11
Installing Windows on your computer brings you candy crushed
在您的电脑上安装Windows会带来candy crushed
Facebook and other unwanted win UI software being polite
Facebook和其他不想要的Win UI软件，客气地说
here the key problem is that
这里的关键问题是，Windows本质上是免费的
Windows is essentially free
making you the product
这使得你成为了产品
So they're profiting off of you by installing spored garbage onto your computer
所以他们通过在你的电脑上安装垃圾软件来从你身上获利
there are two ways to install Windows and not get your face candy crushed
有两种方法可以安装Windows来扳回一局
the first one is to get an iot Enterprise version of Windows 11
第一种方法是安装IOT企业版Windows 11
iot stands for The Internet of Things by the way
顺便说一下，iot代表物联网
that version is intended for Niche
该版本适用于某些原因下使用Windows而非Linux执行自动化任务的企业设备
Enterprise devices performing automated tasks
using Windows instead of Linux for some reason
该版本适用于某些原因下使用Windows而非Linux执行自动化任务的企业设备
Since There is close to non-user input on such devices
由于这类设备几乎没有用户输入
Microsoft have no reason to push sponsored apps
微软没有理由推送赞助应用
and therefore therefore that version is super lean and tidy
因此该版本非常精简和整洁
another benefit of using iot
使用物联网企业版的另一个好处是超长的支持周期
Enterprise is ultra extended support
in fact the iot Enterprise Windows versions
事实上，物联网企业版Windows版本的支持时间最长
are supported the longest
you can also still activate iot Enterprise once and
你还可以使用硬件ID方法一劳永逸地激活IoT Enterprise
for all using the hardware ID method
there are no artificial Hardware
在安装过程中没有人为的硬件要求
requirements during the setup
the Telemetry is turned off by default
遥测功能默认是关闭的
it does not pre-allocate space for updates
它不会为更新、临时文件和存储预先分配空间
and temporary files and Storage
the samba client is much more compatible
samba客户端与旧版本的Windows更加兼容
with the older versions of Windows
it does not randomly start encrypting your
它不会随机使用BitLocker加密你的系统驱动器
system Drive using bitLocker
you can use device Update Center and much much more
你可以使用设备更新中心以及更多功能
it's just so freaking good
这简直太棒了
that version of Windows is what Windows is
那个版本的Windows正是消费者所期望的Windows
supposed to be for consumers
but the consumers are the product and the
但消费者是产品
Enterprises are their customers
企业是他们的客户
so that all makes sense
所以这一切都说得通
don't be a product be a customer instead
不要做产品，要做顾客
the only drawback is that Microsoft Edge is not uninstallable
唯一的缺点是Microsoft Edge无法卸载
but there's a trick if you don't like edge
但如果你不喜欢Edge，这里有个小技巧
thanks to the euro commission you can uninstall Edge in the
多亏了欧盟委员会，你可以在非企业版的欧洲区域卸载Edge
euro region on a nonot Enterprise version
switching Windows versions can be done
通过更改产品密钥可以切换Windows版本
via changing the product key
the region can be changed through settings
通过设置可以更改地区
you're not going to lose any iot perks I mentioned if you switch back after
如果你在卸载那个该死的浏览器后切换回来
uninstalling the godforsaken browser
你不会失去我提到的任何物联网功能
if you guys want I can make a separate video showing how to configure the iot
如果你们想要，我可以单独制作一个视频，展示如何配置企业版
the Enterprise version to be perfect
使其达到完美状态
you can find the download link in the description below
你可以在简介找到下载链接
I'm just afraid they're going to start pushing garbage in that version as well if it becomes mainstream
我只是担心如果那个版本成为主流，他们也会开始推送垃圾内容
but I mean we've got 10 years left right
但我的意思是我们还有10年时间，对吧
the second option is to set a specific region during the setup
第二种方法是在设置过程中指定一个特定区域
you got to select English with a world in the parentheses
你得选择带括号里“世界”字样的英语，才能获得相对干净的Windows版本
to get a relatively clean version of Windows
you'll not get the iot experience with its infinite perks this way
虽然这样你无法体验到物联网版本带来的优点
but you'll get a clean install without any bloat
但你可以获得没有推送的干净版本
until you set the region that's when the floodgates open
直到你设定了区域，那时闸门才会打开
Microsoft hates customers
微软讨厌客户
or and the Microsoft store will not work until you set the region
在你设置地区之前，Microsoft商店将无法使用
so yeah that's the drawback
所以，这就是缺点
the first option is so much better just go iot
最好的选择就是使用iot版本
don't waste your time and nerves
不要浪费你的时间和精力
number nine making windows more verbose
第9，让Windows显示详细信息
anytime I install Windows the first tweaks I apply
每次安装Windows后，我首先应用的调整
are enabling the verbose status and enabling the blue screen display parameters
启用详细状态并启用蓝屏显示参数
I have no idea why that's not enabled by default
我不知道为什么默认情况下没有启用这个功能
I know the verbose status is enabled by default on Windows server
我知道在Windows服务器上默认启用了详细状态
but the blue screen has become less and less informative as time went
但随着时间的推移，蓝屏提供的信息越来越少
so we got to fix that what I mean by that is that since Windows 8
所以我们必须解决这个问题，自从Windows 8以来，蓝屏不再显示错误检查参数
the blue screen no longer shows the bug check parameters
limiting you to the human readable Bug check code and numeration
限制在人类可读的错误检查代码和编号
sometimes that's just not enough
有时这还不够
I don't know why they removed that by default
我不知道他们为什么默认移除了那个
it's almost as if the bug check is supposed to look nice
这就像是错误检查应该看起来不错一样，应该在崩溃时提供尽可能多的信息
instead of giving you as much
information about the crash as possible in the moment
这就像是错误检查应该看起来不错一样，应该在崩溃时提供尽可能多的信息
the fix is simple enough you have to set two registry values shown on the screen
修复方法很简单，你只需设置屏幕上显示的两个注册表值
after you've set those puppies windows will actually tell
在你设置好这些选项后，Windows 会告诉你发生了什么
you what's going on
the verbose shutdown screen is also pretty important because
冗长的关机屏幕也非常重要，因为有时候某个服务就是不想退出，你只能卡在那里看着重启或关机
sometimes a service just doesn't want to
exit and you're just stuck there looking
冗长的关机屏幕也非常重要，因为有时候某个服务就是不想退出，你只能卡在那里看着重启或关机
at restarting or shutting down
what's that obsessive compulsion with hiding
为什么会有这种强迫症般的倾向，隐藏用户可能真正需要用来调试Windows的额外信息
extra information a user might genuinely
need to debug Windows
为什么会有这种强迫症般的倾向，隐藏用户可能真正需要用来调试Windows的额外信息
something happened
到底怎么了
God I really hate that
我真的很讨厌
number 8 emergency restart
第8，紧急重启
Windows is full of mysteries and hidden functionality
Windows充满了神秘的隐藏功能
one such feature is called an emergency restart
其中一个功能称为紧急重启
it's pretty useful of Windows randomly craps itself
对 Windows 来说随机崩溃时还挺有用的
*前提是你按键盘还有反应*
and of course it's hidden
当然这个是隐藏的
to find it you must enter security option AKA press
要找到它，你必须进入安全选项，即按下Ctrl+Alt+Delete
Control Alt Delete
in there at the bottom right you'll find the power options button
在右下角你会找到电源选项按钮
if you just click on the power
如果你只是点击它
icon you'll get all the generics like sleep shutdown restart
只会显示像睡眠，关机，重启按钮
to get to the emergency restart
要显示紧急重启菜单
menu you have to hold down
你要按住Ctrl键然后再点它
control and only then click on the power options
click okay to immediately
点击确定将立即重新启动，所有未保存的数据将会丢失。如非绝对必要，请勿执行此操作
restart any unsaved data will be lost use this only as a last resort
if only you guys knew this existed right
要是你们知道这个存在就好了
for a moment this was a thing since Windows Vista
这是自Windows Vista的一个功能
can also hold control and press
也可以按下同样的关机按键
shutdown there you go emergency restart
显示紧急重启
works just as well
也能用
number 7 the f8 boot options
第7，F8启动选项
I cannot describe how abysmal entering
我无法形容在Windows 7之后进入安全模式变得多么糟糕
the safe mode has become after Windows 7
you have to hold shift at the right
你必须在正确的时刻按住Shift键一段时间
moment for a certain period of time to
then get into troubleshooting and
才能进入可能不起作用的故障排除和恢复选项
recovery options which might not even work
to then click 20 buttons to even
然后点击20个按钮才有机会进入安全模式
have a chance of booting into safe mode
why did you make it so difficult
为什么要搞得这么复杂？
you have invented the f8 and F10 boot menus
你发明了F8和F10启动菜单
they were just so good
它们实在是太棒了
instead you have to get rid of what's consistently
相反，你必须摒弃那些始终有效且超级方便的功能，只是为了用一个主观上更好看的菜单来取代它
working and super convenient only to
replace it with a subjectively better
相反，你必须摒弃那些始终有效且超级方便的功能，只是为了用一个主观上更好看的菜单来取代它
looking menu behind 20 buttons
而这个菜单却藏在20个按钮后面
what's your problem Microsoft
搞什么微软
why is everything becoming a sord
把一切复杂化
anyway this is how you enable the f8 boot menu
无论如何，这是你启用F8启动菜单的方法
you'll need a command prompt with admin
需要一个以管理员运行的命令提示符
rights to bring it back
来将它恢复
by the way the shortcut to run apps
顺便说一下，以管理员身份运行应用程序的快捷键是Ctrl+Shift+Enter，我刚才就是用的这个
as an admin is control shift enter
that's what I just used here
顺便说一下，以管理员身份运行应用程序的快捷键是Ctrl+Shift+Enter，我刚才就是用的这个
it doesn't work Everywhere by the way but it works
顺便说一下，它并不是在所有地方都有效
in some places I guess
但我想在某些地方是有效的
at very least in the crappy windows web search that
至少在连接到互联网的糟糕Windows网页搜索中，找到一个本地文件需要20年时间
connects to the internet and takes 20
years to find a local file
至少在连接到互联网的糟糕Windows网页搜索中，找到一个本地文件需要20年时间
anyway inside the command prompt we have to run the following command
在命令提示符中，我们运行以下命令
so the following command
就是这个命令
the only Legacy thing about that
所以，关于那个菜单的唯一遗留之处就是它已经被我们现在拥有的任何东西所取代
menu is the fact it was superseded by
whatever the hell we have now
所以，关于那个菜单的唯一遗留之处就是它已经被我们现在拥有的任何东西所取代
run the command beautiful the operation completed successfully
运行命令，操作成功完成
and now the next restart
现在重启
will finally be able to use the gorgeous
终于能够使用华丽的F8菜单进入安全模式
f8 menu to put into safe mode
终于能够使用华丽的f8菜单进入安全模式
keeping the troubles shooting and
保持故障排除和恢复选项的完整性，顺便说一下，你仍然可以很好地使用它们
recovery options intact by the way you
can still use those just as well
保持故障排除和恢复选项的完整性，顺便说一下，你仍然可以很好地使用它们
Microsoft makes the most questionable
微软做出了人类所知的最令人质疑的决定
decisions known to men all right
pressing f8
猛按F8
check this out
显示这个
let skip that
跳过
there you go
走你
the Legacy advanced boot options
旧版的高级启动选项
at your fingertips and now you can enter the safe mode with the command prompt
触手可及，现在可以通过命令提示符进入安全模式
using the beautiful f8 boot menu
使用华丽的F8菜单
as you can see the troubleshooting
如你所见，故障排除和恢复选项仍然存在
and recovery options are still present
number 6 the old version of the task manager
第6点，旧版任务管理器
it's an Open Secret Windows consists of layers piled on top of each other
这是一个公开的秘密，Windows 是由层层堆叠组成的
often times we can use that to our advantage
很多时候我们可以利用这一点来获得优势
but before you get your hopes up I'm not talking about the
但在你抱太大希望之前，我说的不是那个骗子戴夫水管工参与的任务管理器
task manager the grifter Dave plumber took a part in
you can run it by just copying it directly from Windows 7 or whatever
你可以直接从Windows 7或其他系统复制它来运行
it works just fine
它工作得很好
if you do hate the new edition of the task manager
如果你确实讨厌新版本的任务管理器
you can revert back to the Windows 8
你可以回退到Windows 8
version of it without any tweaks at all
版本而无需任何配置
I mean the new version is pretty good it
我的意思是新版本相当不错
supports the dark mode but if for some reason you hated
它支持暗黑模式，但如果出于某种原因你不喜欢
you can just run the task manager with a d switch
你可以直接使用 -d 来切换任务管理器
run that and you get the Windows 8
这样你就得到了Windows 8
version of the task manager
版本的任务管理器
enjoy it's not documented at all
有趣，这没有被官方记录
but you can reverse it and find the
但你可以反过来
switch rather easily
很容易地切换
number 5 the Windows boot screen spinner is a font
第5点，Windows启动屏幕的旋转图标是一种字体
Yes you heard that right
是的你没听错
the loading throbber during boot is actually a font
启动时的加载动画实际上是一种字体，太棒了，终于在Windows中找到有效的微妙优化
and that's a great thing finally some subtle optimization that works in Windows
the font is located under C:\Windows\boot\font
字体文件在 C:\Windows\boot\font
and it's called segoe boot Semite
文件名为 segoe boot Semite
we have to to install it first
我们首先安装它
but then it's possible to you it in a character map
之后你可以在字符映射表中找到它
and see the spinner
看到加载动画
我使用该字体搓了一个-->
all right open up the character map

打开字符映射表
look for segoe boot Semite right here
找一下 segoe boot Semite
take a look at the bottom
翻到底部
and you see the spinner
就可以看到加载动画了
very nice
Number 4 The outof box Experience is a customizable web view
第4点，开箱即用体验是一个可定制的网页视图
the outof box Experience in Windows
Windows的开箱体验，也称为FRX或首次运行体验
otherwise known as an FRX or the first
run experience is a web application
是一个用HTML、CSS和JS编写的Web应用程序
written in HTML CSS and JS
I made a video last year reviewing
我去年制作了一个视频，回顾了该应用程序的源代码，发现了一个并不真正隐藏的开发者控制台
the source code for the application and
I found a hidden developer console that's not really hidden
我去年制作了一个视频，回顾了该应用程序的源代码，发现了一个并不真正隐藏的开发者控制台
and since it's a developer application you can zoom in and out look at
由于这是一个开发者应用程序，你可以放大和缩小查看
that and there is uh no limit to how much you can zoom
而且，你可以无限放大
since it's a web view
因为它就是个网页
the g52 x is coming in clutch not
g52 x 关键时刻表现不错，不是赞助，我只是非常喜欢那个鼠标
sponsored by the way I just like that Mouse a lot
what what were we talking about the
我们刚才在说什么来着，关于开发者控制台，你可以按Ctrl+Shift+J来查看开发者控制台
developer console you can press control
shift J to view the developer console
我们刚才在说什么来着，关于开发者控制台，你可以按Ctrl+Shift+J来查看开发者控制台
let me let just zoom in a little bit
让我放大一点点
you can just press control shift J
你可以按Ctrl+Shift+J来查看开发者控制台
to view the developer console
and you're all set you can um select objects
你就可以在开箱即用体验中选择对象来进行调试了
in the out of box experience to debug it
for example let's select the right panel right here
比如选择右侧面板
and we get the more cup
我们就知道这些
as a result we can also find
因此我们也可以发现
the style sheet of an object
对象的样式表
oh there's some uh invisible object right here looks like a grid
这里有些看不见的东西，看起来像个网格
so um let's try selecting the invisible object
试着选择看不见的对象
oh it's an animation and uh
这是负责动画的
we get a we get a CSS file
我们得到了css（负责网页的样式）文件
and the location of it as well
还显示了它的路径
beautiful
太美
基你
okay so there we can also log things
我们还可以修改控制台日志输出
say hi I think that developer console would
输出 hi 我认为开发者控制台对于
be pretty useful for Windows moders but otherwise
Windows修改者来说会非常有用，但除此之外
there is really not much use to it
它真的没有太多用处
another thing I found was the startup animation
我发现的另一件事是启动动画
I located it and apparently it's a 4K video
我找到了它，显然这是一个4K视频
you can press shift F10
按下Shift+F10
then move to Window apps
进入 Window apps 目录
since it's a win UI app or uwp app
因为它是一个Win UI应用或UWP应用
whatever you want to call it
不管你怎么叫它
go to system apps and find microsoft.Cloud experience host
进入到 system apps  和 microsoft.Cloud experience host
can you please oh no no it's called Microsoft Windows
错了，应该是 Microsoft Windows
Cloud experience host I'm sorry guys doing this from memory is kind of difficult
Cloud experience host 很抱歉，凭记忆做这件事有点困难
and um you've got a you got a media
找到 media文件夹，进入
folder right here  cd media
and let's start an explore window
打开文件资源管理器
for convenience sake
为了操作方便
there you go
走你┏ (゜ω゜)=☞
oobe-intro.mp4
check out the properties
看看属性
details that video is um 4500 by 3000
详细信息，视频是4500X3000分辨率
and is a it's a 30 FPS video as well
30帧的视频
that's just so great back when I installed Windows 11 on a pentium 4
那真是太棒了，当初我在奔腾4上安装了Windows 11
I had no clue why it was lagging so bad but
我完全不知道为什么它会这么卡
this answered my question in case you
但这回答了我的问题，以防你们不知道，这真是个懒惰的解决方案
guys don't know that's such a lazy solution
uh since it's a web view
由于是个网页
it would make so much more sense to make
使用CSS动画会更有意义，但你知道的，无薪实习生嘛
use of a CSS animation but you know unpaid interns
I'm not blaming them I'm surprised this thing works at all
我没有责怪他们，我只是惊讶这东西居然还能用
sometimes it breaks not all the time but sometimes
有时候它会坏，不是一直坏，但有时候会坏
number 3 Windows Explorer purposefully slows down indexing in large folders
第3点，Windows 资源管理器故意在大文件夹中减慢索引速度
NTFS is trash it's a garbage
NTFS是垃圾，它是一个在包括可靠性在内的所有方面都输给X的糟糕文件系统
file system that loses to X for in every
possible aspect including reliability
NTFS是垃圾，它是一个在包括可靠性在内的所有方面都输给X的糟糕文件系统
my hard drive wears off faster thanks to
我的硬盘因为NTFS及其带来的额外碎片而磨损得更快
NTFS and extra fragment that comes with it
Windows should support X4 ZFS btrfs
Windows 应该开箱即用地支持 X4 ZFS、btrfs 以及其他所有文件系统
and everything else out of the box
period it's time for NTFS to go
是时候让NTFS退场了，微软，但当然这不会发生
Microsoft but of of course it's not
going to happen they're like three
他们就像三个每天工作4小时的无薪实习生一样在开发Windows
unpaid interns working on Windows 4 hours a day
and there is no incentive to improve
没有改进的动力
but all this aside Windows Explorer is still hardwired to slow file indexing down even further
但除此之外，Windows资源管理器仍然有问题，进一步拖慢了文件索引速度
and I'm not even kidding have you ever wondered why
而且我一点都没开玩笑，你有没有想过为什么Windows资源管理器
Windows Explorer takes an obscene amount of time to load a folder with a large amount of files
加载一个包含大量文件的文件夹会花费如此长的时间
naturally your first and the final
自然地，你的第一反应和最终猜测都会是NTFS是垃圾
guess would be that NTFS is garbage and
that's it because you can't do anything about that
就这样吧，因为你对此无能为力
and you're not wrong NTFS really struggles with a large file count
没错，NTFS在处理大量文件时确实表现不佳
but in reality NTFS isn't that garbage
但实际上NTFS并没有那么糟糕
it's Windows Explorer adding salt to the wound by having the automatic Discovery feature enabled by default
Windows 资源管理器默认启用了自动发现功能，这无异于在伤口上撒盐
what exactly does that do
那到底是做什么的
it changes the view of the folder you're currently in
它会根据文件夹的内容改变你当前所在文件夹的视图
based on the contents of the folder
that means let's say you have 10,000 video files in a folder
这意味着，假设你在一个文件夹中有10,000个视频文件
I do have such a folder on my hard drive it's not called
我的硬盘上确实有这样一个文件夹，不过
homework by the way don't worry it's a
它不叫“作业”，别担心，那是我多年来所有OBS录制的文件夹
folder with all my OBS recordings throughout the years
anyway the automatic folder Discovery will determine
无论如何，自动文件夹发现功能将会启用
it should optimize the Explorer view for video files because
它应该优化资源管理器视图以显示视频文件，因为内容完全是视频文件
the content are entirely video files
meaning it has to take every single video file
意味着它必须处理每一个视频文件
pull the thumbnail out of it
加载缩略图
and then draw it 10,000 times
处理10,000次
just like that do you hear my hard drive?
听到硬盘叫了吗？
oh you probably don't it's going to take more time to load
你可能不知道，加载需要更多时间
that's not only horrible for your mental health
不仅消耗你的精力
that's also horrible for the hard drive it has to spin up for
这对硬盘来说也很糟糕，它必须为这种看似无害的视图变化而启动旋转
that seemingly harmless view change
so how do you turn this travesty off
那么你如何关闭这个
that's an elaborate registry tweak so follow me closely
这是一个复杂的注册表调整，所以请紧跟我的步骤
I'm going to do this on my host because I reinstalled
我要在我的主机上做这件事，因为我最近重装了Windows
Windows recently and the windows web search is garbage
而且Windows的网页搜索很糟糕
and I haven't gotten to apply The tweak yet
我还没有应用这个调整
making a video after three months of absence would be a good excuse
三个月没露面后拍个视频会是个不错的借口，对吧？抱歉了大家
to do that right I'm sorry guys
anyway in the registry editor we have to open the following registry key
无论如何，在注册表编辑器中，我们需要打开以下注册表项
let's navigate towards it
让我们朝它前进
and in here we have two keys
这里有两项
called bags and bagMRU
叫 bags 和 bagMRU
and we need to delete them both
我们要把它们删除
so quick explanation the bags are the shell views
简单解释一下，这些 bags 是外壳视图
that's how they're called in Windows so inside you have
在Windows中它们就是这样命名的，所以里面有你每个文件夹的设置
like settings for every folder
it's detected before and um you can see sniffed folder type generic
之前已经检测到，你可以看到嗅探到的文件夹类型是通用的
so it couldn't determine
因此，它无法准确确定该文件夹的视图，所以决定选择通用的视图
the view exactly for that folder so it
decided to pick the generic View
因此，它无法准确确定该文件夹的视图，所以决定选择通用的视图
and it's a tree like structure right here
像这样的结构有很多
and on top you have the bagMRU key
在顶端可以看到 bagMRU 项
which which is basically a Lup table it's like a small database
基本上是一个Lup表，它就像一个小型数据库
and it has links to the Bags key
并且它与Bags有链接
so we have to delete these guys
所以要删除这些东西
before we do anything else because these
在我们做其他任何事情之前
settings are basically saved in a database
这些设置基本上保存在数据库中
and we have to clean it up we have to drop that database let's go
我们必须清理它，删除那个数据库，让我们开始吧
ahead and delete bags and bagMRU
删除 bags 和 bagMRU
all right it's not going to break anything
完成，没有破坏任何东西
then we have to recreate the Bags key
重新创建 Bags 项
go ahead create a new key call it bags
创建 Bags 项
then inside the bags we have to
在 bags 里，我们要
create another key called all folders
创建 AllFolders 项
that's like a wild card inside
这就像一张万能牌
the all folders key you have to create
在 AllFolders 项里要创建
another sub key called shell
一个子项叫 shell
very intuitive I know that's why I'm saying
非常直观，我知道这就是为什么我这么说
it's elaborate and inside the Shell Key
在shell里，创建一个字符串值叫FolderType
you can finally create a string value called folder type
and we'll call it not specified
填入 NotSpecified
deleting the bags and the bagMRU Keys
删除bags和bagMRU项
essentially flushed the Explorer view database and now we'll end
实质上清空了资源管理器视图数据库，现在我们将为每个文件夹获得一个通用视图
up with a generic view for every folder
and setting folder type not specified
设置为 NotSpecified 将禁用Windows资源管理器的自动文件夹发现功能
here will disable the automatic folder discovery for Windows Explorer
and to apply these settings we have to sign out and sign back into windows
要应用这些设置，我们必须注销并重新登录Windows
so I signed back into my computer let's go ahead and see what
所以我重新登录到电脑上，看看更改后Windows资源管理器发生了什么变化
happened to Windows Explorer after the changes
the window size reset but it's not a big deal we can fix that again
窗口大小重置了，但这没什么大不了的，我们可以再调整回来
all right let's go ahead and enter the folder
好的，进入文件夹看看
check out the properties
查看属性
customize and
自定义
the folder is now optimized for General items
文件夹现在被调整为常规项目
and it loads in an instant
加载速度很快
beautiful that's what we want
这就是我们想要的
before I forget you can also speed up
差点忘了还可以加速
Explorer by pressing f11 twice and
文件资源管理器，只需按两次F11
that's not a joke either so let's go ahead
这不是玩笑，来看看吧
try the performance
试着提高性能
look at this we're browsing through directories
现在在浏览文件夹
real nice
all right
so now we're going to enter the full screen mode and then exit the full
现在全屏后再退出
screen mode Let's see how fast it is now
看看变得多快
it's instantaneous
及时响应
it's not edited it's actually so much faster now
这段视频没有被编辑，这是它真实的响应速度
it's absolutely crazy but that's a proven fact
这很玄学但就是有效
if you enable the full screen mode on Windows Explorer
如果你全屏了文件资源管理器
the directory loading becomes instantaneous
目录加载变得更快
and the Explorer generally starts lagging less
资源管理器的卡顿感变少了
absolutely wild I don't know how they messed it up this bad
简直太疯狂了，真不知道他们怎么会搞砸成这样
number 2 the Windows security questions are plain text
第2点，Windows的安全问题是明文存储的
this is one of my favorite go-to facts
这是我用来说服人们微软其实并不关心Windows时最喜欢用的一个事实
when convincing people Microsoft don't actually care about Windows
I've made an entire video about this you can click on the card to watch it
关于这个我已经做过一个视频，可以点击视频卡片观看（HAF：请到油管观看，我没有搬）
both the security questions and the answers can be
如果拥有管理员权限，安全问题和答案都可以被访问和修改
accessed and modified if you have administrator rights
they are stored in a plain text json and coded in little Indian utf16
它们以纯文本json格式存储，并以小端序utf16编码
residing in the Sam registry key
驻留在Sam注册表项中
I was thinking for quite a bit and decided to put this fact on top of the
我思考了很久，决定把这个事实放在列表的首位，因为它经常被忽视，而且非常有用
list because of how often it is overlooked and how useful it is
shell commands are otherwise known as shell
shell命令也被称为shell快捷方式，Windows有一组硬编码的这些命令
shortcuts and windows has a hardcoded set of these
some of them allow you to reach into really tight crevices or
其中一些可以让你深入到系统看不到的一面
Windows where light doesn't usually shine
there are two types of shell commands
有两种类型的shell命令
the ones with friendly names attached to
一种附带有友好名称
them and the bare CLS ID ones
另一种则是裸的CLS ID
the former is really easy to remember for instance
前者确实很容易记住，比如
let's just open the command prompt and use one of these right now
我们现在就打开命令提示符并使用其中一个
wow it opens the user startup folder
打开了用户启动目录
how convenient let's try another one
多方便啊，再试另一个
that open library list
打开了库列表
simple and elegant
简约而优雅
it's not rocket science
这不是什么高深莫测的事
the latter is where the fun begins
后者才是乐趣的开始
you copy a magic string put it as an argument for
你复制一个神奇的字符串
Windows Explorer and have some crazy
将其作为Windows资源管理器的参数，然后就会打开一个前所未见的窗口
window no one has ever seen before open
it's kind of like a loot box if you don't know what the CLS ID represents before pasting it
这有点像是一个战利品箱，如果你在粘贴之前不知道CLS ID代表什么
so let's copy this puppy right here
所以让我们复制这个小家伙
this opened the window search
打开了 Window 搜索
what about this one
这个捏
this open the Run box
打开了运行框
let's try this one
再试试这个
it opened the old notification area I can dialogue
它打开了旧的通知区域，我可以进行交互
and as you can see it's very broken
如你所见它用不了了
and so on and so forth uh this
诸如此类
is pretty much god mode oh wait god mode
几乎就是上帝模式，等等上帝模式
god mode is actually a shell command
上帝模式实质上是shell命令
how handy look at
多么方便，看啊
there you go that's the god mode
这就是上帝模式
remember that from Windows 7 used to be so much more useful back then
记得Windows 7在那个时候曾经更加实用
but when the Windows settings app hasn't superseded the control panel
但只有在Windows设置应用尚未取代控制面板时
you can find Shell command lists on the internet there is a lot of them
你可以在互联网上找到很多Shell命令列表
like a lot anyway I hope you enjoyed this video
就像这些，希望你喜欢这个视频♥♥♥
原标题：11 INTERESTING FACTS ABOUT WINDOWS 11 原作者：Enderman
原视频上传日期：2025年3月4日
I hope to make more and in a faster Pace
希望我能加快制作视频的速度
uh as I said already I'm a resolve beginner and I don't have much time on
就像我已经说过的，我是Resolve的初学者，而且手头时间不多
hand so I'm trying my best got many cool ideas I'm finishing University soon
所以我正在尽力，有很多很棒的想法，我很快就要大学毕业了
getting my first degree in software engineering pretty hyped looking forward to what life brings
即将获得软件工程的第一学位，非常兴奋，期待生活带来的种种可能
anyway rate the video subscribe if you enjoyed and take care
无论如何，给视频打个分吧，喜欢的话就订阅，生活愉快！
在 Youtube 上关注
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
向所有字幕制作及相关人员道一声辛苦了 (*ˊᗜˋ*)/ᵗᑋᵃᐢᵏ ᵞᵒᵘ*
感谢字幕组的默默耕耘，你们的每一行字都能让更多人能够跨越语言障碍，享受精彩的内容
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！